JESSE LI

△ Boise, ID | ☑ JesseLiCloud@gmail.com | ② 208-957-4157

EDUCATION

B.A in Business Administration Gonzaga University August 2013 - March 2017

-Management Information Systems (MIS), Operations, Finance

-GPA: 3.62

Relevant Courses

- -Database Management: SQL, Data Modeling
- -Information Systems Analysis and Design: Software development life cycle
- -Problem Solving and Programming Techniques: Algorithms
- -Harvard's CS50: Introduction to Computer Science: C, Python, SQL, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

SKILLS

- -Python (Django)
- -Visual Basic.NET
- -HTML/CSS
- -SQL
- -Git

-C

CAREER SUMMARY

Life long learner with a passion for problem solving. After college, I spent two years working as a developer, improving my skillset in object oriented programming, navigating and debugging large code bases, and working closely with clients to satisfy business needs. Recently, I followed my passion in the fitness industry and became an online personal trainer. In this role, I leveraged my developer skillset to learn Python and created an application to provide better services to my clients. Right now, I'm eager for a change and currently looking for new opportunities!

WORK EXPERIENCE

Online Personal Trainer

Justin Bauer Fitness - Remote January 2022 - current

- Built an app using Python and Django to create an ETL solution that automated large amounts of employee research tasks.
- Experience webscraping data with Selenium to send API requests to third party SaaS applications.
- Generated client reports that took this information, organized it in a user friendly GUI, and created client recommendations using data algorithms.
- Experience working remotely in small teams and communicating with over +25 clients on a daily basis.

Software Developer

Fast Enterprises - Columbia, South Carolina June 2017 - July 2019

- Developed, tested, and implemented front-end software solutions using Visual Basic.NET for internal business users and for the South Carolina taxpayer website.
- Developed reports, data fix scripts, and optimized SQL queries using MS SQL Server.
- Responsible for fixing front and back-end bugs spread across over 30 different subsystems.
- Collaborated with internal teams and stakeholders to create optimal solutions for business problems.